What?
おい
Tsukishima...
月島
本字幕由诸神字幕组（kamigami.org）制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:aimie king  翻译:念白白 poopy   校对:木落 时间轴:wcaster
Tsukishima Jinbei Is Here!!
お　お付きの方
Miss...
素晴らしい
Wonderful.
Even if her appearance is not
that of the Kuroageha butterfly,
お姿は黒揚羽でなくとも
この井戸に満ちる力　存分に得られたようですな
she seems to have gained the
power that fills the Well.
お付きの方
Miss... Why?
どういう事です
The princess and I
俺と姫は常世の蟲の力で生を繋いだ同士よ
both survived, thanks to the
power of the Eternal Insect.
俺に歯向う小鼠を姫が始末する事に不思議などない
There's nothing strange about her
slaying a little rat that opposes me.
姫の記憶はもうなくなってしまったのだ
Her memories are gone.
Jin
What?
なんと
お付きの方
Miss...
ご自分の手を
Your hand...
Look at your palm...
その手のひらをご覧ください
それは自分で刻まれたもののはず
You carved that there yourself.
Jin
思い出してください
Please remember, miss!
お付きの方
I don't know it.
知らぬ
Huh?
Miss...
お付きの方
そんな事は
That's impossible...
仁兵衛君
Jinbei-kun!
月島
Tsukishima!
戯れ事をお耳に入れて申し訳ありません
I apologize for making you
listen to such nonsense.
さ　我が主が大阪でお待ちです
Now, our lord waits in Oosaka.
勝手に話進めてんじゃねーよ
Don't think you can leave
without dealing with us!
このまま行かせる訳が無いだろう
We won't just let you go.
止めてみせる　全力で
I'll stop you... Using my full power!
There is no need to sully the princess's hands.
姫君のお手を煩わせはしません
Now behold.
胸に刻んでおけ
貴様らが俺を足止めした事で
Because you have delayed me here,
I will reduce everything in Kishuu to ash!
この紀州は　全てが塵となる
なんだ
What?
I can crush the likes of you in an instant.
貴様らごとき　一瞬で捻り潰してくれる
Wait...
ちょっと
仁兵衛君　無理をするな
Jinbei-kun, don't be stupid!
I'm going to be stupid!
無理は　します
駄目だよ
No...
蟲ですら然様に飛んで火には入らぬぞ
Not even a moth would leap
into a flame such as this.
Keep winning until you die!
死ぬまで勝つ
Now is the time!
今がその時
Even if...
たとえ　死んでも
I die!
I will...
真田には 勝って見せます
win against Sanada!
The first has fallen quite quickly...
呆気なかったな　一匹目は
I thought he'd be more fun to kill.
もう少し殺し甲斐があると思ったが
You will follow him!
貴様らも後を追え
野郎
You bastard...
I won't die unless I kill you first!
貴様をやらずにあの世なんかに行くか
懺切り　クライマックス
Repentance Slash Climax!
Plus...
プラス　花鳥風流　飛燕一閃
Flowering Wind-style Draw: Flying Swallow!
What?
なんだ
It's like there's some kind of wall.
壁があるみてぇだ
Matsukichi!
末吉　為吉
Tamekichi!
Full-Power Slap!
全力突っ張り
I won't die before I win...
勝つまで死ねないよ
Full-Throttle Fire!
ファイヤー　フルスラットル
Me, too!
私だって　死ぬまで勝つ
I'll win until I die...
No matter what it takes!
どんな手を使ってでも
Princess Camellia: Chinpou Spray!
姫椿　珍宝大噴射
言っただろう　無駄だ
I told you... It's useless.
どうすりゃいいんだ
What do we do?
Mugai-kun!
無涯君
塵外刀　砕氷
Jingaitou: Shattered Ice!
塵外刀　夢幻光
Jingaitou: Phantasm Light!
これは　才蔵の力か
This is Saizou's power?
だが俺には効かん
But it won't work on me!
無涯さん
Mugai-san!
奴の能力は割れた
His powers have been revealed.
そうだね
Indeed.
What do you mean?
どういう事
His shock waves are simply invisible.
奴の衝撃波の正体は目に見えぬだけ
攻撃を受け止めてる間なら少しは見える
While he's blocking our attacks,
you can just barely see them.
Black powder...
黒い粉
これが衝撃波の正体
That's what his shock waves are?
いかにも
Indeed.
これは鉄の鱗粉
These are iron scales.
だがそれを知った所でどうする
But what good will knowing that do you?
The shock waves turned into insects!
衝撃波が蟲になりやがった
秘技　小太刀千花
Secret Technique: Thousand Bladed Flowers!
ムシケラに用はない
I've no time for these little maggots!
You are my next prey!
お前が次なる骸になれ
体が
I can't move...
Potato-boy...
芋坊主
The Eternal Insect's power which filled the Well
井戸に満ちる常世の蟲の力で蘇り
覚醒したというのか
has revived and awakened him?
It's just like on Hachijo Island.
八丈島の時と同じだ
やはり仁兵衛君には蟲狩の血が流れているんだ
I was right... Jinbei-kun bears
the blood of Insect Hunters.
蟲狩って　無涯さんと同じ
Insect Hunters? Like Mugai-san?
ああ　母上の血筋だろう
Yes, probably from his mother's side.
だとしても　なんであんな格好に
But why would it turn him into that?
The Eternal Insect cursed the clan of Insect
Hunters and bathed in their blood.
蟲狩は常世の蟲に呪われ その血を浴びた一族
That's why they respond to
the Eternal Insect's power.
だからこそ常世の蟲の力に反応する
The wounded Jinbei-kun woke
after he came into contact
傷を負った仁兵衛君は
八丈島でも同じ常世の蟲の力を持つ
with the Insect Magistrate's hair,
which is imbued with the same power.
蟲奉行様の髪に反応して覚醒したんだ
Then the power of the Eternal Insect
flows through his blood, as well?
こいつの体にも流れているというのか　常世の蟲の力が
全てが　全てが憎い
I hate everything... Everything!
Everything is my enemy.
全てが敵
That voice...
この声は
全てが敵
Everything is my enemy.
倒す
Defeat them.
敵は全て倒す
Defeat all the enemies.
These are the thoughts of the insect
connected to the servant!
お付きの方と因縁のあるあの蟲の思い
Everything is my enemy.
全てが敵
Defeat them.
倒す
八丈島で自分は　この思いに飲まれたのだ
On Hachijo Island, the thoughts
overwhelmed me...
敵は全て倒す
飲まれてはいけない
I can't let that happen again!
飲まれては
I can't...
何をしている 芋坊主
What are you doing,
potato-boy?!
貴様は死ぬまでに勝つ武士になるのだろう
Aren't you going to be a samurai
who wins until he dies?
無涯殿　ありがとうございます
Mugai-dono, thank you!
Even if it kills me, Sanada Yukimura,
死んでも　真田幸村　貴様は必ず倒す
I shall defeat you!
Nonsense.
ほざけ
I shall go back with the princess.
俺は姫を連れて帰る
常世の蟲のおられる大阪へ
On my pride as a samurai, I swear
that I shall go to Oosaka,
武士の矜持をかけて
where the Eternal Insect waits.
貴様は武士などではない
You are no samurai!
武士とは人の助けになるもの
A samurai helps others...
自分はお付きの方を必ずお救いする
I will save the servant!
What is that?
なんですかあれは
よくわかんないけど
I don't know...
But run away!
逃げるのですよ
Your battle bores me.
お主の戦いは見ていてつまらぬ
I will defeat him.
こいつは妾が倒す
お付きの方は自分に御任せください
Please leave the servant to me.
でも
But...
約束したのです
I promised that I would protect her,
no matter what happened!
何があろうと　必ずお守りすると
妾に向かって来ようとは
You are unworthy of fighting me.
身の程を知れ
Our opponent is...
僕達の相手は
真田幸村
Sanada Yukimura!
You fight me!
俺が相手だ
紫陽花玉　十蓮華
Hydrangea Bomb: Ten Lotuses!
全力　大横綱突っ張りー
Full-Power Great Yokodzuna Slap!
The closer he comes,
the more the poison he inhales.
妾に近づけば近づく程 毒に侵されるというのに
それなのになぜこの者は
So why does he not even try
to draw his sword?
刀さえ抜かぬのだ
貴様は馬鹿か
Are you an idiot?
You must not lose your memories!
あなたは絶対記憶を無くしてはいけません
If it's the poison that's making you forget...
忘れているのがもしその毒のせいなら
その毒　この身で吸い取ってみせます
I'll absorb it all into my body!
（いつの日か今よりも　強くなりたい）
自分はあなたをお守りすると約束しました
I promised I would protect you...
（ただひとつの願い　胸に咲く炎）
I want to protect your memories, too!
あなたの思い出も守りたいのです
All my memories with you are
flashing through my mind.
自分の頭の中には　あなたとの思い出が蘇っています
どの思いでも　鮮やかに
I remember them all so clearly!
Stop it... You cannot absorb the poison!
やめよ　毒を吸い取ることなどできぬ
Do you remember, Miss?
覚えているでしょう　お付の方
（何もできなかった日に　胸の誓いは生まれた）
Stop it!
やめよう
Then I'll take more of your poison...
なら　もっと　あなたの毒を　吸い取ってみせる
（決してもう逃げ出さないと　ただひたすら前を向くと
傷つき倒れ　また立ち上がる　諦めなど知らぬ者に
春は何度でも
この先に何がある　見えなくていい
Jin
一途なまなざしが　炎を灯すよ）
A heart that cares for others...
思いやる心か
It was your heart that made me remember...
思い出させてくれたのはお主の心だ
Jinbei...
仁兵衛
記憶がお戻りになったのか
Her memories have returned?
だが記憶が戻ったとしても　姫は大阪に戻る運命なのだ
But even if they have,
she is destined to return to Oosaka.
We won't allow that!
んなことさせねぇ
月島だってあんなにやったんだから
After all that Tsukishima has done,
蟲奉行様は　私達が守る
we will protect the Magistrate!
貴様らに守れるものなど　万に一つもない
You can protect no one...
この紀州の者共　数千の命もな
Not even the thousands in Kishuu!
What?
何？！
わらわは思い出したのだ
I remember now...
人々の命を守るという務めもな
My duty to protect the lives of the people!
何を　愚かな
How stupid.
あなたの力を持ってしても　何も変えることはできません
Even your power changes nothing.
ご覧に入れましょう　紀州が滅びる姿を
Observe, as Kishuu is destroyed!
させるかよ
I won't let you!
Compassion Slash!
慈合い斬り
紫陽花玉
Hydrangea Blossoms!
Full-Power Slap!
全力突っ張り
塵外刀　瀑布
Jingaitou: Cascade!
花鳥風流居合い　天罰
Flowering Wind-style Draw:
Divine Punishment!
兄ちゃん　そろそろ起きな
Time to wake up, kiddo!
月島はできる子でしょう
You can do it, can't you, Tsukishima?
Jinbei-kun!
仁兵衛君
もう　朝よ　月島
It's morning, Tsukishima!
やつを殺せば　足掻く気もなくなるか
So if I kill him, they'll lose their will to fight?
おはようございます
Good morning!
ここで眠るわけにはいきません
I cannot sleep right now!
眠るなら真田幸村　お前を倒してからだ
I'll go back to sleep after I defeat you,
Sanada Yukimura!
Nonsense.
ほざけ　周りを見よ　紀州は終わりだ
Look around you... Kishuu is finished.
そして姫は　必ず俺が大阪へ連れて帰る
And I will take the princess back to Oosaka.
人の生き方は貴様になど決められない
You can't decide how others will live!
紀州の人々の生き方も　お付の方の生き方も
Not the people of Kishuu...
And not the servant!
まもなく　町は消し飛ぶ
The town won't last much longer.
紀州の人間とて既に諦めているわ
The people of Kishuu have already given up.
そんなことはない
That isn't true...
自分は感じる　こうしている今も
I can feel it.
Even now, they haven't lost hope!
皆さんは希望を失ってはいない
Let's go, Sanada Yukimura!
行くぞ　真田幸村
Given that poisoned body of yours,
I can't believe you can fight so well.
毒を浴びた体で　まだそのように戦えるとは
だが力尽きた瞬間
But the moment you tire,
you and Kishuu will be turned to ash!
貴様らも紀州も　すべて塵になるぞ
自分は臆さぬ
I will not give up...
臆せば　後ろの守るべき方々まで恐怖に飲まれてしまう
Or the people behind me that I'm
protecting will be lost to terror!
バカが　貴様は恐れも身の程も知らず
Idiot.
You know neither fear nor your proper place.
自ら死に向かうのみのバカだ
You're merely an idiot, rushing to your death!
バカでも　自分は人々の不安を消し去る
Even if I am an idiot,
I must be a shining star.
One that erases their fear!
綺羅星に　ならねばならぬ
Even if it's impossible, keep thinking it.
無理でも思い続け　言い続け　やり続け
Keep saying it!
Keep doing it...
This is the time!
今こそならねばならぬ時
雑魚は俺達に　任せてくれ
Leave the rest of them to us!
思い切りやりなさい　月島
Get him, Tsukishima!
月島はできる子　全力連続突っ張り
You can do it, Tsukishima!
Full-Power Combo Slap!
仁兵衛
Jinbei!
今こそ紀州の皆さんの苦しみの数々を晴らす時
Now it's time to end the
Kishuu people's suffering...
そして大岡殿の　無念も
And to avenge Oooka-dono!
うるさいネズミが
Silence, rat.
消えろ
Begone!
Can you not die, human?
貴様という人間は　死なないのか
死ぬまで　勝つ
I will keep winning until I die!
Tsukishima-style: Mt. Fuji Storm!
月島流　富嶽山嵐
Tsukishima-style: Mt. Fuji Rising Dragon!
月島流　富嶽昇龍
Tsukishima-style: Mt. Fuji Meteor Drop!
月島流　富嶽隕石落とし
紀州の皆さん　真田幸村を討ち取りました
Citizens of Kishuu, I have
defeated Sanada Yukimura!
Thank you! Thank you!
ありがとう
Thank you!
お付の方　まもなく江戸です
Miss, we're nearly to Edo.
初めてかもしれぬな
This may be the first time...
今までわらわは運命に流されてきた
I've always let fate rule my life.
だが今は江戸で自分で帰りたいと思う
But now, I wish to return to Edo, too.
I'm looking forward to my days in Edo.
江戸での日々が楽しみなのだ
仁兵衛　実はわらわはな
Jinbei, I'm actually...
自分も楽しみです
I look forward to it, as well!
いつの日か　蟲奉行様に江戸の青空を
Someday, I'll get to show the Insect Magistrate
皆と一緒に見せて差し上げることが
Edo's blue skies, alongside everyone else!
I'm looking at them now.
もう見ている
Welcome back, Jinbei-sama!
友よ　友よ　君の中に
I'm back, Oharu-dono!
悲しいほどの純粋さを見た
日の暮れた学舎の片隅で
We haven't been in Edo for five minutes.
汗まみれの素振りをしてたな
Lucky pervert.
友よ　友よ　君の中に
By now, it's a daily occurrence.
Jinbei-kun, an insect has appeared!
笑えるほどの情熱を見た
Get to work...
「俺には夢があるんだ」と　馬鹿でかい声で叫んでいたな
君の街に朝日が
What?
Here I go!
Bye!
昇ってきたとしたのならば
Time for the Insect Magistrate's
to return to work!
賑やかな街の中を
Yeah!
走り抜けていったじゃないか
お帰りなさい　仁兵様
君の街に夜更けが
The End
お春殿　戻ってまいりました
やってきたのだとしたのならば
大通りを抜けたところの
あんた　江戸に帰ってきた途端　何やってんの
河原で語ったな
ラッキー助べえ
そうだろ　友よ
もはや日課だな
仁兵衛君　蟲が出た
お務めだよ
友よ　友よ　君の中に
何と　行ってまいります
綺麗な真心を見た
はい
さぁ　蟲奉行所は　本日もお務めだ
大切な命を抱きしめながら
おう
真剣な顔をしてるな